<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home-Automation on Projects and Coding Adventures</title>
    <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/tags/home-automation.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home-Automation on Projects and Coding Adventures</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 15:57:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/tags/home-automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automating our garage door with an ESP2866 and Home Assistant</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2022/10/24/automating-our-garage-door-with-an-esp2866-and-home-assistant.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 15:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2022/10/24/automating-our-garage-door-with-an-esp2866-and-home-assistant.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/ox-hugo/garage-door-feature.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve got a house again, I can really start playing with home automation&#xA;projects a lot more. The first thing I plan to do is come up with something to&#xA;monitor and automate the garage door, as I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; panicked from not&#xA;remembering whether I&amp;rsquo;d closed it when leaving the house. It turned out I had&#xA;closed it, but I can definitely do without that anxiety. What better way to&#xA;remove that anxiety than by being able to remotely monitor and control the door!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating My Apartment With Home Assistant</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2019/06/27/automating-my-apartment-with-home-assistant.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 18:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2019/06/27/automating-my-apartment-with-home-assistant.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2018/03/13/hue-wake-up.html&#34;&gt;posted about&lt;/a&gt; my experiments with the Phillips Hue API&#xA;to create an automated morning sunrise effect. The end result was&#xA;nice, but all that mucking about with their HTTP APIs was a hassle any&#xA;time I wanted to tweak something. I wanted to define what I wanted in&#xA;a more declarative style, and have all the API calls managed behind&#xA;the scenes. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.home-assistant.io/&#34;&gt;Home Assistant&lt;/a&gt; allowed me to do exactly that, and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Does The Phillips Hue Wake-Up Feature Work?</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2018/03/13/hue-wake-up.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2018/03/13/hue-wake-up.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got myself a set of Phillips Hue White and Color Ambiance&#xA;lights. One of the features I was looking forward to in particular&#xA;(besides playing with all the color options) was setting a wake-up&#xA;alarm with the lights gradually brightening. This was pretty painless&#xA;to get set up using the phone app. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with the result,&#xA;but there&amp;rsquo;s certainly some things I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind tweaking. For&#xA;example, the initial brightness of the bulbs (at the lowest setting)&#xA;still seems a bit bright, so I might want to delay the bedside lamps&#xA;and let the more distant lamp start fading in first. I also want to&#xA;see if I can fiddle it into transitioning between some colors to get&#xA;more of a sunrise effect (perhaps &amp;ldquo;rising&amp;rdquo; from the other side of the&#xA;room, with the light spreading towards the head of the bed).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
