<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Projects and Coding Adventures</title>
    <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/blog.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Projects and Coding Adventures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trans Day of Visibility 2022</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2022/03/31/trans-day-of-visibility-2022.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2022/03/31/trans-day-of-visibility-2022.html</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to feel positive about this year&amp;rsquo;s Transgender Day of Visibility. On the one hand, trans visibility is extremely important. It&amp;rsquo;s because of out trans people that I was able to understand my own identity. The more cis people really see, talk to, and come to understand trans people, the easier it will be for them to understand that we&amp;rsquo;re, well, just people. Transitioning is a beautiful thing. Look at any set of photos trans people share, and you&amp;rsquo;ll see that they&amp;rsquo;re not just happier, but more vibrant, more full of life, and so very genuinely themselves!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating My Apartment With Home Assistant</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2019/06/27/automating-my-apartment-with-home-assistant.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 18:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2019/06/27/automating-my-apartment-with-home-assistant.html</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I posted about my experiments with the Phillips Hue API to create an automated morning sunrise effect. The end result was nice, but all that mucking about with their HTTP APIs was a hassle any time I wanted to tweak something. I wanted to define what I wanted in a more declarative style, and have all the API calls managed behind the scenes. Home Assistant allowed me to do exactly that, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does The Phillips Hue Wake-Up Feature Work?</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2018/03/13/hue-wake-up.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2018/03/13/hue-wake-up.html</guid>
      <description>I recently got myself a set of Phillips Hue White and Color Ambiance lights. One of the features I was looking forward to in particular (besides playing with all the color options) was setting a wake-up alarm with the lights gradually brightening. This was pretty painless to get set up using the phone app. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with the result, but there&amp;rsquo;s certainly some things I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind tweaking. For example, the initial brightness of the bulbs (at the lowest setting) still seems a bit bright, so I might want to delay the bedside lamps and let the more distant lamp start fading in first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaner Recursive HTTP Requests with Elm Tasks</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2018/01/23/cleaner-recursive-http-with-elm-tasks.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2018/01/23/cleaner-recursive-http-with-elm-tasks.html</guid>
      <description>Continued from part one, Recursive HTTP Requests with Elm.
In my last post, I described my first pass at building a library to fetch data from a paginated JSON REST API. It worked, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too clean. In particular, the handling of the multiple pages and concatenation of results was left up to the calling code. Ideally, both of these concerns should be handled by the library, letting the application focus on working with a full result set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recursive HTTP Requests with Elm</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2018/01/22/recursive-http-with-elm.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2018/01/22/recursive-http-with-elm.html</guid>
      <description>So I got the idea in my head that I wanted to pull data from the GitLab / GitHub APIs in my Elm app. This seemed straightforward enough; just wire up an HTTP request and a JSON decoder, and off I go. Then I remember, oh crap&amp;hellip; like any sensible API with a potentially huge amount of data behind it, the results come back paginated. For anyone unfamiliar, this means that a single API request for a list of, say, repositories, is only going to return up to some maximum number of results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use a different theme when publishing Org files</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2016/02/23/org-publish-with-theme.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2016/02/23/org-publish-with-theme.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using material-theme lately, and I sometimes switch around, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found that solarized produces the best exported code block results. To avoid having to remember to switch themes when exporting, I wrote a quick wrapper for org-export to do it for me:
(defun my/with-theme (theme fn &amp;amp;rest args) (let ((current-themes custom-enabled-themes)) (mapcar #&amp;#39;disable-theme custom-enabled-themes) (load-theme theme t) (let ((result (apply fn args))) (mapcar #&amp;#39;disable-theme custom-enabled-themes) (mapcar (lambda (theme) (load-theme theme t)) current-themes) result))) (advice-add #&amp;#39;org-export-to-file :around (apply-partially #&amp;#39;my/with-theme &amp;#39;solarized-dark)) (advice-add #&amp;#39;org-export-to-buffer :around (apply-partially #&amp;#39;my/with-theme &amp;#39;solarized-dark)) Voilà, no more bizarrely formatted code block exports from whatever theme I might have loaded at the time :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing Git Graphs with Graphviz and Org-Mode</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2015/07/12/git-graphs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2015/07/12/git-graphs.html</guid>
      <description>Digging through Derek Feichtinger&amp;rsquo;s org-babel examples (which I came across via irreal.org), I found he had some great examples of displaying git-style graphs using graphviz. I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be a fun exercise to generate my own graphs based on his graphviz source using elisp, and point it at actual git repos.
Getting Started I started out with the goal of building a simple graph showing a mainline branch and a topic branch forked from it and eventually merged back in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Files And Configuration In Sync</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2015/04/20/syncing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2015/04/20/syncing.html</guid>
      <description>I have a few computers I use on a daily basis, and I like to keep the same emacs and shell configuration on all of them, along with my org files and a handful of scripts. Since I&amp;rsquo;m sure other people have this problem as well, I&amp;rsquo;ll share what I&amp;rsquo;m doing so anyone can learn from (or criticise) my solutions.
Git for configuration and projects I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer, so keeping things in git just makes sense to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday Puzzle</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2015/04/18/birthday-puzzle.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2015/04/18/birthday-puzzle.html</guid>
      <description>This logic puzzle has been floating around the internet lately. When I caught wind of it, I thought it would be a great exercise to tackle using Prolog. I&amp;rsquo;m not especially good with the language yet, so it added to the challenge a bit, but it was a pretty worthwhile undertaking. When I got stumped, I discovered that mapping out the birthdays into a grid helped me visualize the problem and ultimately solve it, so I&amp;rsquo;ve included that with my prolog code so you can see how I arrived at the answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coders at Work</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2015/01/28/coders-at-work.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2015/01/28/coders-at-work.html</guid>
      <description>A few days before leaving work for a week and a half of flying and cruising to escape frigid Pennsylvania, I came across a Joe Armstrong quote during my regularly scheduled slacking off on twitter and Hacker News. I&amp;rsquo;d come across a couple times before, only this time I noticed it had a source link. This led me to discovering (and shortly thereafter, buying) Peter Seibel&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Coders at Work &amp;ndash; Reflections on the Craft of Programming&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventuring Through SICP</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2015/01/01/sicp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2015/01/01/sicp.html</guid>
      <description>Back in May, a coworker and I got the idea to start up a little seminar after work every couple of weeks with the plan to set aside some time to learn and discuss new ideas together, along with anyone else who cared to join us.
Learning Together Over the past several months, we&amp;rsquo;ve read our way through the first three chapters of the book, watched the related video lectures, and did (most of) the exercises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Organized with Org Mode</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2014/11/25/getting-organized-with-org-mode.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2014/11/25/getting-organized-with-org-mode.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Emacs Org mode for nearly a year now. For a while I mostly just used it to take and organize notes, but over time I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered it&amp;rsquo;s an incredibly useful tool for managing projects and tasks, writing and publishing documents, keeping track of time and todo lists, and maintaining a journal.
Project Management Most of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Org mode for has been breaking down large projects at work into tasks and subtasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erlang: The Movie</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2013/11/27/erlang-the-movie.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2013/11/27/erlang-the-movie.html</guid>
      <description>Hopping through Joe Armstrong&amp;rsquo;s blog, I happened across Erlang: The Movie. More programming languages need videos like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Functional Programming, Part One</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2012/04/09/learning-functional-programming-part-one.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2012/04/09/learning-functional-programming-part-one.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-one-lambdas-in-my-python&#34;&gt;Part One: Lambdas? In my Python?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to take a stab at learning some
functional programming. I&amp;rsquo;d been doing python for a few years (and
completely falling in love with it), and so I&amp;rsquo;d been exposed to a few
functional concepts it offers - primarily higher-order functions and list
comprehensions, both of which allow for very clear, concise and powerful code.
Since that&amp;rsquo;s where I started my journey, that&amp;rsquo;s where my post will begin as
well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transmission, RSS, and XBMC</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2011/04/27/transmission-rss-and-xbmc.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2011/04/27/transmission-rss-and-xbmc.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xbmc.org/&#34;&gt;XBMC&lt;/a&gt;. My pc (currently running Ubuntu 10.04) has taken root in my
living room, piping all my movies and tv shows straight to my HDTV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While my pc is set up as a DVR using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mythtv.org&#34;&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt; to record shows off my FIOS box, it tends to be a little unreliable, which can suck when it&amp;rsquo;s time to catch up on Daily Show and Colbert episodes.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.transmissionbt.com/&#34;&gt;Transmission&lt;/a&gt; set up for a while for all my torrenting needs, and
I&amp;rsquo;ve even written an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/correl/Transmission-XBMC&#34;&gt;XBMC script to manage torrents&lt;/a&gt;, so I got to looking for
tools to track tv show torrent rss feeds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meh.php</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2011/04/27/meh-php.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2011/04/27/meh-php.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;?php if (!defined(&amp;#39;meh&amp;#39;)) define(&amp;#39;meh&amp;#39;, null); class Meh { public function __set($name, $value) { } public function __get($name) { return meh; } public function __isset($name) { return true || false; } public function __unset($name) { } public function __call($name, $arguments) { return meh; } public function __callStatic($name, $arguments) { return meh; } } $bwuh = new Meh(); $bwuh-&amp;gt;give_a_shit(); echo $bwuh-&amp;gt;concerns; class SuperDuperBillingProcessor extends Meh {} $p = new SuperDuperBillingProcessor(); $p-&amp;gt;calculateEverything(); $p-&amp;gt;profit(); </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potatoes and Portal Guns</title>
      <link>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2011/04/26/potatoes-and-portal-guns.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://correl.phoenixinquis.net/2011/04/26/potatoes-and-portal-guns.html</guid>
      <description>Got my hands on Portal 2 and finished a run through the single player campaign. Was a lot of fun, the characters were bursting with humor and personality. Just like the first game, it was hard to stop playing. Unlike the first game, it&amp;rsquo;s got some length, so I stayed up late a couple nights with my eyes glued to the television. I already want to play through it again to find any little things I my tired eyes may have missed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
